(Kamran)
Kamran Razmavar presents another strange
argument, and Jesus did NOT meet
(Naran)
But the existence of countries and
peoples is NOT established this way.
(Naran)
And now let's debunk this myth about
Greater Armenia, which allegedly
(Other Speaker)
According to Wikipedia, Greater Armenia
therefore did not exist from the fourth
(Naran)
And somewhere in the middle of these 80
years, he was born in Bethlehem, by the
(Kamran)
Strangely enough, Jesus did NOT meet a
single Armenian. There is nothing
(Kamran)
But there are NO Armenians, NO Armenia,
and there is NO need to insert it there,
(Naran)
The Gospels are NOT a list of all the
peoples of the Near East. The absence of
(Naran)
Moreover, the name Armenia is recorded
approximately 5 centuries before the
(Naran)
Around 520 BC, Darius the First left the
Behistun inscription.
(Other Speaker)
In the Dri-nepersis text, the country is
called 'Armina or the inhabitant of
(Naran)
The Encyclopaedia Iranica translates the
latter as Armenian. Now to Kamran's
(Naran)
Even this is NOT true if we speak about
Biblical translations in general.
(Other Speaker)
In the classic English translation of
the King James Bible, in 2 Kings 19:37
(Naran)
In modern translations, in these same
places, the land of Ararat is more often
(Naran)
And this shows the main problem of
Kamran's argument.
(Naran)
Different linguistic and translation
traditions can convey ancient
(Naran)
This is also seen in the Behistun
inscription. Ancient Persian versions
(Other Speaker)
There are independent Greek testimonies.
Herodotus from the fifth century BC
(Other Speaker)
Xenophon in the early 4th century BC
repeatedly writes about Armenia and
(Naran)
Therefore, Kamran's question of why
Jesus did NOT meet Armenians
(Naran)
Persian and Greek sources record Armenia
and Armenians centuries before Christ.
(Naran)
And the attempt to prove the absence of
Armenia with the word 'Ararat' collapses
(Other Speaker)
the canonization of the Sussex
countries.
(Other Speaker)
Word for Word, print for print.
This is exactly how it is.
(Other Speaker)
Like the newer bibles you see now,
they've all been changed.
(Other Speaker)
They've modified translated,
re-translated, all that stuff.
(Other Speaker)
But this is like the original original.
Where they have the trees of
civilization.
(Other Speaker)
Not like where the first man was found
but civilization, modern civilization.
(Other Speaker)
If you look down here, look.
You got no zark.
(Other Speaker)
And look at that.
or mean you.